<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 18:43:47 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTex. Markup language</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 18:43:47 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/latex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;latex-markup-language&#34;&gt;LaTex. Markup language&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TEX is a publishing system created by the American mathematician and programmer Donald E. Knuth. TEX was developed with two main goals in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;allow everyone to create high-quality publications with reasonable efforts for this;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;provide a tool that allows you to create externally identical publications on all computers in the present and in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TEX is famous for its extreme stability, working on various types of computers and almost complete absence of errors.
The TEX version number tends to π and is now equal to 3.14159.
In many technical communities, especially computer,
mathematical, physical and chemical, TEX is recognized
as a de facto standard. A huge number of books are published using TEX
including books published by Cambridge University Press,
Elsever, Oxford University Press or Springer. A large number of scientific and technical journals are published using TEX, allowing authors of publications should send their articles directly in the TEX document format
LATEX (in the ASCII environment, LaTeX is written) is a markup language and
a document preparation system that uses TEX as a layout engine. LATEX automates many aspects of document layout, such
as automatic numbering of pages, tables, illustrations, formulas, cross-references, headers, footers, index, table of contents and references. The LATEX system additionally
contains a large set of TEX macros that facilitate the creation of complex documents. The first version of LATEX was written in 1984 by Leslie Lamport and has since become the dominant way of preparing TEX publications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My last week 2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/my_last_week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 18:38:43 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/my_last_week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-last-week&#34;&gt;My last week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My week was productive. I started studying Chinese language courses. I also attended a master class on making cakes and confectionery. Besides that, I was glad to meet new people and have a good time with them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 21:21:27 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;git-version-control-systems&#34;&gt;Git. Version control systems.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git is a distributed version control system that tracks changes in any set of computer files, usually used for coordinating work among programmers collaboratively developing source code during software development. Its goals include speed, data integrity, and support for distributed, non-linear workflows (thousands of parallel branches running on different systems).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version Control Systems (VCS) are used when several people work on one project. Usually, the main project tree is stored in a local or remote repository, to which access is configured for project participants. When making changes to the project content, the version control system allows you to fix them, combine changes made by different project participants, roll back to any earlier version of the project, if required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In classical version control systems, a centralized model is used, assuming a single repository for storing files. Most version control functions are performed by a special server. The project participant (user) receives the version of files he needs before starting work through certain commands. After making changes, the user places the new version in the repository. At the same time, previous versions are not deleted from the central repository and you can return to them at any time. The server can save not the full version of the modified files, but perform so-called delta compression — save only changes between successive versions, which reduces the amount of data stored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version control systems support the ability to track and resolve conflicts that may arise when several people are working on a single file. You can merge (merge) changes made by different participants (automatically or manually), manually select the desired version, cancel the changes altogether or lock files for modification. Depending on the settings, the lock does not allow other users to get a working copy or prevents changing the working copy of the file by means of the OS file system, thus providing privileged access to only one user working with the file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version control systems can also provide additional, more flexible functionality. For example, they can support working with multiple versions of a single file, keeping a common history of changes up to the point of branching versions and their own change histories of each branch. In addition, information is usually available about which of the participants, when and which ones are changed&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My last week</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/my-last-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 20:42:58 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/my-last-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My week has been eventful and productive. I met friends, visited an interesting exhibition and started reading a new book. Besides, my parents visited me and I had a good time with them&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
